tremormedia.com 2017-06-29

# Privacy Policy

Introduction 

This privacy policy describes the types of information that Tremor Video, Inc. (“we” or “Tremor Video”), collects on our corporate website and through our video advertising services. It also describes how that information is used and the choices we offer to users, or you, about the collection and use of such information.

### PRIVACY POLICY FOR THE TREMOR VIDEO CORPORATE WEBSITE 

[www.tremorvideo.com](https://www.tremorvideo.com/)  is the corporate website of Tremor Video. This website (the “Tremor Video Site” or “Site”) provides users, typically current and prospective customers, partners, and job seekers, with information about our products and services, and gives users the opportunity to contact us for further information.

This privacy policy describes the types of information that Tremor Video collects on the Site and how that information is used. Tremor Video reserves the right to revise this privacy policy from time to time by posting the changes on the Site. Your continued use of the Site constitutes your acceptance of the current posted privacy policy. If you have questions about this privacy policy, please email us at privacy@tremorvideo.com.

What information does the Tremor Video Site collect?

_Personally_ _identifiable information_  
Personally identifiable information is information that identifies a user as a specific individual, such as a name, email address, mailing address, or phone number, or data that you provide that Tremor Video can reasonably link to other information that you provide in order to personally identify you.

The Tremor Video Site collects personally identifiable information about users only if a user voluntarily provides that information to the Site. Personally identifiable information is collected on the Tremor Video Site in various instances including, without limitation:

  * _Information requests._ A Site user, typically a current or prospective customer, partner, or job seeker, submits an inquiry to the Site using the “Contact Us”, “Request a Demo” and “sign me up” functions, and provides his or her name, address, email address, and/or telephone number so that Tremor Video is able to respond.
  * _Comment on_ _news,_ _blog_ _,_ _or other_ _posting._ A user posts a comment in the blog or news section of the Site, and submits his or her name and email address with the post.
  * _Subscribe to email newsletter_ _._ To subscribe to the Tremor Video email newsletter, a user provides his or her name, email address, and other contact information. Each newsletter will provide the user with the option of unsubscribing from future newsletters.
  * _Subscription feed_ _._ A user subscribes to the Site’s subscription function by providing his or her email address.
  * _Access to Tremor Video’s web-based client interface_. A current Tremor Video client accesses the client/customer-only areas of the Site by submitting his or her username and password.
  * _Request for feedback._ From time to time, the Tremor Video Site may ask users for voluntary feedback that will help us improve the Site. In connection with such feedback, a user may choose to provide optional name and contact information.
  * _Promotions, sweepstakes, or contests._ From time to time, Tremor Video may sponsor or co-sponsor promotions, sweepstakes or contests, in response to which a user may provide information, such as his or her name, email address, or other contact information, and/or to answer certain questions on an entry form.

_Non-personally identifiable information_

Non-personally identifiable information includes demographic information (such as age, gender, city, or state) and a user’s clickstream information. The Tremor Video Site collects information about users and stores it in log files. This information includes non-personally identifiable information that your browser automatically sends whenever you visit this Site, including information about your web request, your IP address, your browser type, browser language, date, and time of the request.

How does Tremor Video use information collected by the Tremor Video Site?

_Personally_ _identifiable information_  
Tremor Video uses the personally identifiable information you provide to respond to your inquiries and requests, and to keep accurate records concerning the services you are requesting through the Tremor Video Site.

_Non-personally identifiable information_  
Tremor Video generally uses non-personally identifiable information in aggregated form to help measure the Tremor Video Site’s performance and effectiveness, and to improve its features and usefulness.

With whom does Tremor Video share personally identifiable information collected on the Tremor Video Site?

Tremor Video does not share the personally identifiable information that you provide to the Tremor Video Site, other than with its service providers that help Tremor Video provide the services that you request, such as delivery of our email newsletters, and to help Tremor Video manage information provided by job seekers for possible employment with us.

Tremor Video may transfer or assign the information it collects on the Site to any successor-in-interest to Tremor Video (such as a company that acquires Tremor Video), or internally to one or more affiliates (such as a corporate subsidiary or parent).Tremor Video may also disclose personally identifiable information about a user if it determines that an applicable law, regulation or legal process requires it, or if Tremor Video determines that it needs to share such information to protect or enforce Tremor Video’s rights or the rights of another user.

What else should I know about privacy?

_Security_

Tremor Video maintains safeguards to protect the security, integrity and privacy of the personally identifiable information within our reasonable control.  However, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, while we strive to protect your information, please be advised that Tremor Video assumes no responsibility or liability for disclosure of your information due to errors in transmission, unauthorized third-party access, or other causes beyond Tremor Video’s reasonable control.

_Links to_ _other websites_

Tremor Video does not control the data collection policies of any third party website linked to the Tremor Video Site. If you click on a link or an advertisement, the privacy policy of the website to which you link will govern the collection and use of your information by that website’s operators. Tremor Video assumes no responsibility or liability for the actions of such third parties with respect to their use of your information or otherwise.

_Collection of_ _information_ _from_ _minors_

The Tremor Video Site is directed to, and intended for use by, adults only. We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of thirteen. If we become aware that we have inadvertently received personally identifiable information from a user under the age of thirteen, we will delete such information from our records.

ACCEPTANCE OF PRIVACY POLICY FOR THE TREMOR VIDEO SITE

When you use the Tremor Video Site, you are accepting the terms and conditions of this privacy policy, and Tremor Video will have the right to use your information as described in this privacy policy. If you do not agree to have your information used in any of the ways described in this privacy policy, you must discontinue use of the Tremor Video Site.

### PRIVACY POLICY FOR TREMOR VIDEO’S SERVICES

What does Tremor Video do?

Tremor Video is an online video advertising software company. Tremor Video’s advertiser customers engage us to display their video ads in streaming content that is featured on websites and applications across the Internet, including content that is viewable on mobile devices, tablets and TVs.  Sellers utilize our solutions to improve their yield and maximize the value of their video advertising inventory.

How does Tremor Video’s software select the video ads that I see?

Tremor Video’s proprietary ad serving software displays video ads, typically immediately before or during the streaming of featured content on a website or application. The video ad is provided to Tremor Video by an advertiser, and the featured content is shown on the websites and applications of a content provider.

Our advertisers may specify where, when, and in what context they want their video ads to be displayed. These specifications are sometimes called targeting parameters.

Tremor Video uses its proprietary ad serving software to target, select and deliver ads according to the advertisers’ specifications. In order to optimize the delivery of a video ad, Tremor Video’s software collects and analyzes information provided by the website or application publisher, by the user’s computer or device, and advertiser, among other sources, which, in turn, is automatically recorded (logged) by the  servers of Tremor Video. Examples of the types of information we may collect and store in the server logs are the following: browser type and language, operating system, Internet Protocol address (for example, to identify a user’s general location), page URL and referral URL, video player size, video content (such as video title, description, category), date and time of request, internet service provider (such as Verizon FiOS), and advertising cookies.  When selecting, targeting and delivering ads, Tremor Video does not actively collect, and does not use or store personally identifiable information about a user.

Tremor Video’s ad serving software may use cookies, web beacons, and other similar technologies to select, target, and measure the effectiveness of advertisements, including when determining what ads to present so that they may best relate to the possible preferences and interests of users based on information collected across multiple websites that they visit. We call this practice of collecting data about a user’s online activities to deliver advertising targeted to a user’s likely interests “interest-based advertising.”

A “cookie” is generally a small text file that is sent to a user’s computer. Cookies are commonly assigned by online services, such as websites or ad technologies, to recognize a computer that they have encountered before. A cookie is associated with a specific site domain, a specific computer, and a specific Internet browser program. Our advertising cookies operate anonymously: we do not use them to gather the user’s name, street address, e-mail address, or telephone number(s).

A “web beacon” is a small piece of code placed on web pages that can be used, among other things, to count the users who visit the web page, or to deliver a cookie to the browser of a user viewing that page.

How does Tremor Video deliver ads to mobile applications?

In the case of advertisements targeted, selected, and delivered to mobile applications, for example, apps on a smartphone, the Tremor Video software may collect information provided by the user’s mobile device, including certain unique mobile operating system advertising IDs, such as Apple’s Identifier for Advertising ID (IDFA) or Google’s Android Advertising ID (AAID) to target, select, and deliver advertisements.  Other examples of information we may collect to target, select and deliver advertisements may be the type of the mobile device and the location of a mobile device if a user enables collection of precise location data through the available features on that mobile device.

How does Tremor Video recognize a user across multiple devices? 

Tremor Video’s software may, in some cases, be able to infer within a reasonable probability that a particular computer or device may be correlated with the same Tremor Video identifier (e.g., cookie, advertising IDs, IP address) that we have previously associated to another computer or device. In such cases, Tremor Video’s software may be able to infer that a device (e.g _._ a computer) and another device (e.g. a smartphone) are used by the same user. Where such an inference can be made, we may use this information to target, select and deliver ads across multiple computers and devices. This is sometimes referred to as cross-device advertising.

What are examples of ad choices Tremor Video offers to users?

  * Opt out of Tremor Video’s cookie used for interest-based advertising by clicking on the “[Opt Out](https://www.tremorvideo.com/privacy-policy)” button at the top of this page.
  * Opt out of cookies used for interest-based advertising by a number of online advertising companies at the [Digital Advertising Alliance Consumer Opt-Out Page for Online Behavioral Advertising](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/).
  * Manage the settings on your smartphone. Find out how you may opt of mobile application interest - based advertising at the [Mobile App Opt - Out Guide](https://www.tremorvideo.com/mobile-app-opt-out-guide) for more information. Please be aware that your smartphone may not offer the same features.
  * Set your browser to reject cookies, and remove the cookies that have already been placed. Find out how at [All About Cookies](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) for more information.

Four things to know about opting out:

  * You will still see video ads from Tremor Video after you opt out. However, the ads that you see will be less relevant to you.
  * You will need to opt out separately for each browser and each device. There is not a single opt out that governs all your browsers and devices.
  * If you change your browser or device, you will need to opt out again for each new browser and device. The new browser and device does not inherit your prior settings.
  * If you delete the opt out cookie from your browser, you will need to opt out again from that browser.

How do we use third-party service providers?

Tremor Video and its advertisers may use third-party ad service providers to help deliver advertisements. These ad service providers use cookies, web beacons, or other technologies to select, target, deliver, and measure the effectiveness of advertisements, including when determining what ads to present so that they may best relate to the possible preferences and interests of users. Tremor Video may use data that ad service providers collect in the delivery of interest-based advertisements. This data is non-personally identifiable information and is used to deliver advertisements that may be more relevant to a user.

Tremor Video may share non-personally identifiable information about users gathered by means of cookies, web beacons, or other technologies, including anonymous identifiers used in connection with mobile applications, with certain ad service providers so that they can help Tremor Video deliver more relevant advertisements, including for cross - device advertising. The use of cookies, web beacons, or other technologies by other ad service providers is subject to their respective privacy policies, and not by the privacy policy of Tremor Video. You can find out more about ad service providers and the choices you have about their technologies by clicking on the links at the bottom of this privacy policy. Similarly, the publishers to which we deliver an ad are subject to their own privacy policies and not the privacy policy of Tremor Video.

Is information transferred to Tremor Video successors and affiliates?

Tremor Video may transfer or assign the information it collects in connection with its business to any successor-in-interest to Tremor Video (such as a company that acquires Tremor Video), or internally to one or more affiliates (such as a corporate subsidiary or parent). Tremor Video may also disclose information if it determines that an applicable law, regulation, or legal process requires it, or if Tremor Video determines that it needs to share such information to protect or enforce Tremor Video’s rights or the rights of our customers or another user.

ABOUT THIS PRIVACY POLICY

Tremor Video reserves the right to revise this privacy policy from time to time. If you have questions or concerns about this privacy policy, please email us at privacy@tremorvideo.com or write to us at Tremor Video, Inc., Attention: Privacy, 1501 Broadway, New York, NY 10036.

_US Self-regulatory program for online behavioral advertising_

Tremor Video follows the Digital Advertising Alliance industry privacy standards for online behavioral advertising. To learn more about the program and its principles, [visit the Digital Advertising Alliance](http://www.aboutads.info/).

_US-EU Safe Harbor Framework_

Tremor Video has registered with the U.S. Department of Commerce’s US-EU Safe Harbor program, and we adhere to the Safe Harbor Framework regarding the collection, use, and retention of data received from the European Union (EU). In the event there is a written complaint submitted to Tremor Video regarding the transfer of personal data from the EU that Tremor Video is unable to resolve, we will cooperate with the appropriate regulatory authorities, including the EU Data Protection Authorities. [Visit the US-EU Safe Harbor program](http://export.gov/safeharbor/) to learn more.

_Third-party ad service providers_

The following third-party ad service providers may use cookies, web beacons, and other technologies in connection with advertisements delivered by Tremor Video. Click on the links below to find out more about their practices, and the choices they provide to you:
